Guide to the Asociacion De Sacerdotes Hispanos de Nueva York Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Asociacion De Sacerdotes Hispanos de Nueva York Papers
1972-1984
Asociacion de Sacerdotes Hispanos de Nueva York.
1.5 linear ft (ca. 1500 items in 3 boxes).
Columbia University, Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078364
History
"The Association of Hispanic Priests in the Archdiocese of New York is a fraternal organization that seeks to serve the spiritual, pastoral, cultural and humanitarian needs and concerns of the New York Hispanic community."
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, musical scores, audio tape, cassettes, and related printed materials concerning Hispanic culture, immigration problems, parish conflicts, intercultural confrontation, and linguistic discrimination. Included are correspondence with the members, by-laws, minutes of meetings, membership lists, and records of all the organizations activities. Of particular interest are the files of the Cultura Popular Hispana-Gala de la Hispanidad, October 20, 1984, which included a competition for original manuscripts and musical scores for both religious and secular poetry.
Arrangement
Arranged by series.
Subjects
Catholic Church--Dioceses--New York (State)--New York.; Catholic Church--Clergy--Societies, etc.; Hispanic American Catholics--New York (State)--New York.; Christian poetry, Spanish.; Hispanic-American poetry.; Audio cassettes; Scores
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1985 Papers Rev. Josè M. San Sebastian Gift
Gift of the Rev. Jose' M. San Sebastian, 1985.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Records, 1972-1983
  - PRIMEROS ESTATUTOS, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - NUEVOS ESTATUTOS DE ASH, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - LISTAS DE SOCIOS DE ASH (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - CONVOCATORIAS, 1971 December-1976 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CONVOCATORIAS, MINUTAS, LISTAS DE ASISTENCIAS, 1976 April-1982 September (Box 1, Folder 5 to 8)
  - CONVOCATORIAS, ACTAS, LISTAS DE ASISTENCIAS, 1982 September-1983 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ASUNTO CLERO ADJUNTO (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PADRES APOSTOLADO NORDESTE - PAN (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ENCUESTAS REALIZADAS
    - FIESTA DE SAN JUAN, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - FECHA REUNIONES, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - OBJETIVOS ASH, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - FECHA REUNIONES, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - PLANTEAMIENTOS PASTORALES
    - ILEGALES, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - CONGRESO HISPANO DIOCESANO-HAYDEE BORGES, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - CAMINO-MOVIMIENTO JUVENIL, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - MOVIMIENTO FAMILIAR CRISTIANO, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - EVANGELIZACION Y COMUNIDAD CRISTIANA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - CURSILLOS PARA SACERDOTES HISPANOS
    - RELIGION POPULAR PUERTORRIQUENA-S.ARROYO, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - IGLESIA AMERICANA, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - PASTORAL LIFE PROGRAM, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - CORRESPONDENCIA DE ASH, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - CORRESPONDENCIA, 1979-1983 September (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - CELEBRACION DECIMO ANIVERSARIO DE ASH, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - DEPOSITO DE DOCUMENTOS DE INTERES PASTORAL, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series II: Records, 1983-1984
  - ACTAS Y CONVOCATORIAS DE ASAMBLEAS Y JUNTAS ORDINARIAS, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - BALANCE ACTIVIDADES, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CORRESPONDENCIA, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - DOCUMENTOS REDACTADOS: BASES CONSTITUCIONALES DEL APOSTOLADO HISPANO,PROPUESTA DE ASH SOBRE SACERDOTES ADJUNTOS, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - VIDA ESPIRITUAL: RETIROS PARA SACERDOTES HISPANOS, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - REUNIONES DE ASH CON SACERDOTES NO HISPANOS, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - GALA DE LA HISPANIDAD-PREMIOS DE CULTURA POPULAR HISPANA: POESIA T MUSICA, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - INVENTARIO DE LOS ARCHIVOS DE ASH, 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ASUNTO PARROQUIA SANTA ROSA DE LIMA, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MANUSCRITOS CONCURSO CULTURA POPULAR HISPANAGALA DE LA HISPANIDAD, 1984 OCTUBRE 20
    - SECCION PREMIOS T FINALISTAS (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - SECCION DE POESIA RELIGIOSA (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - SECCION DEPOESIA POPULAR (Box 3, Folder 11)